parkopedia.com 2018-06-23

# Privacy Policy

Parkopedia Limited (including its affiliates) ( **Parkopedia** , **we** , **our** , **us** or the **Company** ) is the controller of your personal data and is committed to protecting and respecting the privacy of its Users. We believe that you have a right to know our practices regarding the information we may collect and use when you use the Service.

This Privacy Policy ( **Policy** ) relates to services provided through our website and application ( **Services** ) and sets out the basis on which the personal data collected from you, or that you provide to Us will be processed by Us. This Policy also describes Our practices for collecting, using, maintaining and processing information.

Parkopedia is a cloud-based web platform that enables Users to find the closest parking to their destination, tells them how much it will cost and whether the space is available, and where possible allows for the Reservation of a parking space globally (the **Service** ).

A User may be either an entity, for example a car park operator who maintains facility data in the Parkopedia Service ( **Operator(s)** ) or a member of the public who uses the Parkopedia Service to search or reserve parking ( **End User(s)** ) (Operator and End User shall collectively be referred to as **Users** or **you** ).

Users who wish to use the Service may be asked to provide Parkopedia, with certain information including Personal Information as further detailed in this Privacy Policy (“Data”). Our use of this Data in connection with the Services will be undertaken in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it.

By using our Services, you acknowledge you have read and understood this privacy policy.

There are two categories of data that we collect from our Users.

Data we collect when using the Service;

The first type of Data is non-identifiable and anonymous information ( **Non-personal Information** ). We are not aware of the identity of the User from which we have collected Non- Personal Information. Non-Personal Information is any unconcealed information which is available to us while Users are using the Service. Non-personal Information which is being gathered consists of technical information and behavioural information which may include

  * a User’s anonymised Internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet
  * the uniform resource locators (URL)
  * operating system
  * type of browser
  * browser plug-in types and versions
  * Flash version
  * the period of time the User visited the website

**Non-Personal Information is collected through your use of our Service**. This means that then you are using our Service we are aware of it and may gather, collect and record the information relating to such usage, either independently or through the help of third-party services such as Google Analytics. Data you give us;

The second category of data is individually identifiable information ( **Personal information** );

Personal information of a User which is being gathered can consist of; username, password, email, facebook ID, IP address, first name , last name, postcode, vehicle registration mark, and Credit card details.

**We will never sell your Personal Information to third parties. (for more information see the Section titled: “Who we share your data with”).**

You do not have any legal obligation to provide any information to Parkopedia and can use our Services without providing Personal Information. However, we require certain information in order to provide additional Services to you. Login credentials (email and username) are required to access Service such as; application premium subscriptions, to participate in gamification of reporting parking coverage, and to book a parking reservation. We may keep such Personal Information in a database which will be owned and maintained by Us (the **Data Controller** ) in accordance with this policy (for more information see the Section titled: How long we keep your personal data).

Parkopedia may also collect the email addresses and retain communication from users who contact Us via email or messenger services.

**Personal Information is collected because you provide it to Us voluntarily**. We collect Personal Information from you when you would like to operate the elements of our additional Service which are described below.

When you are using our Services we will use your data for the following reasons;

* * *

## Allowing you to use www.parkopedia.com to search for parking information (either as a registered or unregistered user). Purpose - website monitoring, website performance analytics, website customisation

### Types of Data

**Non-personal data**

  * Internet protocol (IP) address, anonymised
  * the uniform resource locators (URL),
  * operating system,
  * type of browser,
  * browser plug-in types and versions,
  * the period of time the User visited the website,
  * Session Cookie

**Personal data**

  * Internet protocol (IP) address

### Lawful basis for processing including basis of legitimate interest

Non-personal data cannot be used to identify you personally. As such we do not require a lawful basis for processing such data.

We will process personal data when you search for parking availability on the lawful basis that it is necessary for us to perform a contract with you

Personal data may also be processed by us on the basis of it being necessary for our legitimate interests, where we process such data in order to analyse and review how the website is used and operates, so that we can improve the functionality of our website.

* * *

_To register you as a new customer/client - New account_

### Types of Data

**Personal data**

  * Username
  * Email
  * Password

### Lawful basis for processing including basis of legitimate interest

We will process such personal data on the lawful basis that it is necessary for us to perform a contract with you

* * *

_**To register you as a new customer/client - using Facebook authentication**_

### Types of Data

**Personal data**

  * Facebook id
  * Email

### Lawful basis for processing including basis of legitimate interest

We will process such personal data on the lawful basis that it is necessary for us to perform a contract with you

* * *

## To allow you to book, and manage, a reservation

### Types of Data

**Personal data**

  * Postcode
  * Vehicle registration
  * First & Last name

**Passed to third party**

Stripe

  * Credit Card details (tokenised via Stripe)

Reservation Partners

  * Email or Unique User ID
  * Vehicle registration
  * First & Last name

### Lawful basis for processing including basis of legitimate interest

We will process such personal data on the lawful basis that it is necessary for us to perform a contract with you

* * *

## To allow you to email us for support

### Types of Data

**Personal data**

  * email
  * Password

### Lawful basis for processing including basis of legitimate interest

We will process such personal data on the lawful basis that it is necessary for us to perform a contract with you

* * *

## To create an online user account for you

### Types of Data

**Personal data**

  * email
  * Password

### Lawful basis for processing including basis of legitimate interest

We will process such personal data on the lawful basis that it is necessary for us to perform a contract with you

* * *

## To create an online user account for you

### Types of Data

**Personal data**

  * Email
  * Name

### Lawful basis for processing including basis of legitimate interest

We will process such personal data on the lawful basis that it is necessary for us to perform a contract with you

* * *

Please note that Personal Information may be either deleted or retained in an aggregated manner without being linked to any identifiers or Personal Information, depending on technical commercial capability. Such information may continue to be used by Us for the purpose of operating the Service.

If we need to use your personal data for unrelated purposes, we will notify you and we will explain the legal basis which allows us to do so.

Please note that we may process your personal data without your knowledge or consent, in compliance with the above rules, where this is required or permitted by law.

**Third parties who we may share your data with:**

Although Parkopedia processes transactions when You make a parking reservation, the credit card details are never known to us. Through the signup process credit card details are provided by You direct to our payment authorisation partner, Stripe (<https://stripe.com/us/privacy/>) who securely manage the details and provide Us with a token key which we store against your details for future transactions.

Email and vehicle registration details are shared with reservation partners to enable the booking of parking reservations to fulfil our contractual obligations with You. By default we do not ask you for your first and last name, however if this is required in order to make a parking reservation we will prompt you to make that decision to provide the additional details.

Non-Personal anonymised data is shared with ‘Google Analytics’ to allow Parkopedia to analyse the usage and performance of its Services.

We may also **disclose your personal information to third parties:**

  * in our corporate group who may act as joint controllers or processors and who may be based inside or outside the EU;

  * If Parkopedia’s assets are acquired by a third party, including by way of a merger, share acquisition, asset purchase or any similar transaction, in which case personal data held by it about its customers will be one of the transferred assets;

  * Including service providers who may act as processors based inside or outside the EU and who provide IT, system administration and other services.

  * Including professional advisers who may act as processors including lawyers, bankers, auditors and insurers based inside or outside the EU who provide consultancy, banking, legal, insurance and accounting services.

  * If Parkopedia has a good faith belief that access, use, preservation or disclosure of such information is reasonably necessary to

  * satisfy any applicable law, regulation, legal process or enforceable governmental request, enforce applicable Terms and Conditions, including investigation of potential violations thereof. Such parties may include HM Revenue & Customs, regulators and other authorities who may act as processors based inside or outside the EU who require reporting of processing activities in certain circumstances,

  * detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues, or

  * protect against imminent harm to the rights, property or safety of Parkopedia, including Users or the public as required or permitted by law.

  * In order to enforce or apply our terms of supply terms and other agreements with you

  * For avoidance of doubt, Parkopedia may transfer and disclose Non-Personal Information to third parties at its own discretion, which does not serve to identify individuals for example number of Users who searched for a particular area, or how many Users clicked on a advertisement or sponsored link.

We require all third parties to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in accordance with the law. We do not allow our third-party service providers to use your personal data for their own purposes and only permit them to process your personal data for specified purposes and in accordance with our instructions.

The Data we collect from you ( **personal** and **non-personal** ) is hosted on the Amazon AWS Cloud data centre in the European Economic Area (EEA) and is compliant with the ISO 27001 security standard (<https://aws.amazon.com/compliance/>). Advanced security features are not only inherently built into the Amazon AWS cloud, but also into the Parkopedia Services.

In addition to the above, the Data we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area (EEA) in order to fulfil our Service commitment with You.

Where your Data is transferred outside of the EEA, in particular with Parkopedia’s reservation service partners (‘Data Processors’) we will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your Data is subject to appropriate safeguards and that at least one of the following safeguards is implemented:

  * We will only transfer your personal data to countries that have been deemed to provide an adequate level of protection for personal data by the European Commission. For further details, see European Commission: Adequacy of the protection of personal data in non-EU countries.

  * Where we use certain service providers, we may use specific contracts approved by the European Commission which give personal data the same protection it has in Europe. For further details, see European Commission: Model contracts for the transfer of personal data to third countries.

  * Where we use providers based in the US, we may transfer data to them if they are part of the Privacy Shield which requires them to provide similar protection to personal data shared between the Europe and the US. For further details, see European Commission: EU-US Privacy Shield.

Your data may also be accessible to Parkopedia customer support staff who are based outside of the EU. Where customer support is required, your data will remain in the EEA in order to safeguard your privacy rights.

We may transfer your personal data outside of the EEA, in order to:

  * Enable us to provide you with the Services (via Data Processors) and fulfil our contract with you

  * Fulfil any legal obligations which require us to make that transfer

  * Facilitate the operation of our group business, where it is in our legitimate interests and we have concluded these are not overridden by your rights.

**Security**

Parkopedia takes great care in implementing, enforcing and maintaining the security of our Service, and of the personal data that our Users provide us. We take appropriate measures to ensure that all personal data is kept secure including security measures to prevent personal data from being accidentally lost, used/modified/destroyed or accessed in an unauthorised way, for the duration of your use of our Services. We limit access to your personal data to those who have a genuine business need to know it. Those processing your information will do so only in an authorised manner and are subject to a duty of confidentiality.

Parkopedia will act in accordance with the **Guidance from the UK Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO) on personal data security breaches under the General Data Protection Regulation**. We also have procedures in place to deal with any suspected data security breach. We shall act in accordance with these policies to notify you and any applicable regulator, in the event of a suspected data security breach where We are legally required to do so. In the event of a security breach Parkopedia will promptly take remedial measures to restore the security of personal data, and to limit the unauthorised access or illegal transfer of personal data.

**Keeping your personal data up to date**

If your personal details change you may update them by contacting Us using the contact details below.

We will endeavour to update your personal data within thirty (30) days of any new or updated personal data being provided to Us, in order to ensure that the personal data We hold about you is as accurate and up to date as possible.

**How long we keep your personal data**

We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.

To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.

By law we have to keep basic information about our customers (including Contact, Identity, Financial and Transaction Data) for at least six years after they cease being customers for tax purposes.

Details of other retention periods for different aspects of your personal data are contained in our retention policy which you can request from us by contacting [privacy@parkopedia.com](mailto://privacy@parkopedia.com).

In some circumstances you can ask us to delete your data and in some circumstances we may anonymise your personal data (so that it can no longer be associated with you) for research or statistical purposes in which case we may use this information indefinitely without further notice to you.

Some metadata and statistical information concerning the use of the Service will not be deleted and shall be kept in an anonymized manner. This data is not subject to the personal information procedures in this policy and may be retained by Us. We will not be able to identify you from this data. Some data may also be retained on our third-party service providers’ servers until deleted in accordance with their privacy policy and their retention policy.

Parkopedia reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time. The most current version of our Privacy Policy will always be posted at <https://www.parkopedia.com/privacy/>. All other changes to this Privacy Policy are effective as of the stated “Last Revised” date and your continued use of Services will constitute your active acceptance of the changes to the Privacy Policy.

When the User visits the Parkopedia Website we transmit one or more cookies securely to the computer (“local storage”) over an encrypted connection. This allows us to enable automatic activation of certain website features, to enhance the User’s experience and interaction with the Website by storing User preferences.

The cookies used by the Service are created per session and do not include any personal information about you, other than your session key (set to expire after 60 minutes) and the ability to login again quickly. For your information it is possible to disable cookies by adjusting your browser, however it will reduce the services available to you.

If you want to disable cookies on our site, you need to change your browser settings to reject cookies. How you can do this will depend on the browser you use. Further details on how to disable cookies can be found here;

  * Internet Explorer – http://windows.microsoft.com/en-GB/internet-explorer/delete-manage-cookies

  * Google Chrome – https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en

  * Firefox – https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences

  * Safari – http://help.apple.com/safari/mac/8.0/#/sfri11471

The effect of disabling cookies depends on which cookies you disable but, in general, the Service may not operate properly if cookies are switched off.

We may collect information about your computer, including where available an anonymised IP address, operating system and browser type, for system administration and analytics for internal reporting purposes.

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our website. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address, or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, please [contact us](https://www.parkopedia.com/contact-us/).

The Parkopedia Service does not knowingly collect or solicit information or data from children under the age of 16 or knowingly allow children under the age of 16 to register for the Service. If you are under 16, do not register or attempt to register for any Parkopedia Service. If we learn that we have collected Personal Data from a child under the age of 16, we reserve the right to delete that Personal Information and User account as soon as reasonably practicable without any liability to Parkopedia from any User. If you believe that we might have collected or been sent information from a minor under the age of 16, please contact us on [privacy@parkopedia.com](mailto://privacy@parkopedia.com).

Under the **General Data Protection Regulation (‘GDPR’)** you have a number of important rights free of charge. In summary, those include rights to:

  * access to your personal data and to certain other supplementary information that this Policy is already designed to address

  * require Us to correct any incomplete or inaccurate personal data which We hold

  * require the erasure of personal data concerning you in certain situations. Note, however, that we may not always be able to comply with your request of erasure for specific legal reasons which will be notified to you, if applicable, at the time of your request.

  * receive the personal data concerning you which you have provided to Us, in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and have the right to transmit those data to a third party in certain situations

  * object at any time to processing of personal data concerning you for direct marketing through following the unsubscribe link contained in our marketing emails.

  * object to decisions being taken by automated means which produce legal effects concerning you or similarly significantly affect you

  * object in certain other situations to our continued processing of your personal data

  * otherwise restrict our processing of your personal data in certain circumstances

  * withdraw consent at any time in respect of personal data being processed by us on the basis of us having your consent to do so

  * claim compensation for damages caused by our breach of any data protection laws

For further information on each of those rights, including the circumstances in which they apply, see the [Guidance from the UK Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO) on individuals rights under the General Data Protection Regulation](http://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/guide-to-the-general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr/individual-rights/).

If you would like to exercise any of those rights, please:

  * contact us using our Contact details below

  * let Us have enough information to identify you

  * let Us have proof of your identity. Where you are a user of our Services you should email us from the email address that you used to register with Parkopedia. Receipt of an email from this address will usually be sufficient to confirm your identity. For queries relating to parking reservations we may request further proof of identification either relating to the transactions that you made or your vehicle registration details and

  * let Us know the information to which your request relates.

We try to respond to all legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally it may take us longer than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated.

Firstly, we hope that you never have the situation arise where you wish to complain about our use of your personal information. However, if you do, then in the first instance we hope that we can resolve any query or concern that you raise with Us.

If not, then the [General Data Protection Regulation](http://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/PDF/?uri=CELEX:32016R0679&from=EN) also gives you the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority (Data Protection Authority in your jurisdiction) in case of a breach of any EU data protection and privacy regulations. The supervisory authority in the UK is the Information Commissioner who may be contacted at <https://ico.org.uk/concerns/> or telephone: 0303 123 1113.

Our full contact details are:

Full name of legal entity: **Parkopedia Limited** Postal address: 232 Sladepool Farm Road, Birmingham, West Midlands, B14 5EE

All questions, comments and requests regarding this Privacy Policy should be addressed to privacy@parkopedia.com.

**Last Revised: May 10th, 2018**
